

Senior Software Engineer seeking roles in Software Development, Project
Management, Web Development, Database Architect, Application Programming,
Requirement Gathering, Process Improvement, PHP, HTML, CSS, Javascript, MySQL,
MongoDB, Node.js, AWS



Current Designation: Senior Software Engineer Total Experience: 5 Year(s) 5 Month(s)

Current Company: Codilar Technologies Notice Period: 2 Months

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore Highest Degree: BCA [Computers]

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Senior Software Engineer, Software Developer, Software Development, Project Management, Web Development, Database Architect, Application Programming, Requirement Gathering, Process Improvement, Workflow

Management, MySQL, PHP, HTML, CSS, Javascript

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 22-Jan-21 Last Modified: 22-Jan-21

Summary

5+ years of experience as a Backend Developer made recommendations to modify the program to enhance effectiveness toward the business result. Provided insightful knowledge of business process analysis (As-Is, To-Be) and design Liaised with stakeholders during problem diagnosis, requirements gathering, detailed level design, development, system test, and production implementation to ensure that optimal resolutions were achieved.

Enhanced modules delivered to production by rewriting and developing new code to improve the efficiency and effectiveness of systems. Followed the project life cycle methodology defined under the process framework, ensuring that the project will get delivered within the timeline.

Working as Pimcore Consultant with MH. Alshaya Co. for 2+ years.

Work Experience

Codilar Technologies as Senior Software Engineer Feb 2020 to Till Date

Key Result Areas:

- Developing new features as per business requirements
- Delivering work on time to meet the project deadline
- Deploying code in different environments
- Managing module customization and improvisation

Codilar Technologies as Software Engineer Jul 2018 to Jan 2020

Digital Adworks as Senior Web Developer Jan 2018 to Jun 2018

Key Result Areas:

- Analyzed project requirements and prepared development workflow
- Designed and developed Database Architecture
- Managed Integration Testing and deployment of overall applications

- Worked on projects like We Design Architects, Totoodo - Store Locator, Totoodo - Franchise Software, SBN Travels, Sekhar Group, Self Ride, Avhni Fixit and more

Digital Adworks as Web Developer

Oct 2016 to Dec 2017

Y3K Imaginations as PHP Developer Jun 2015 to Aug 2016

Key Result Areas:

- Analyzed project requirements and prepared development workflow
- Designed and developed Database Architecture
- Managed Integration Testing and deployment of overall applications
- Worked on projects like SHIATS University, Hotel Regency, Smart Vision Infra

Education

UG: BCA (Computers) from Swami Vivekanand Subharti University in 2014

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
PHP, Node JS, Laravel, Pimcore, ExpresJS			
Codeigniter, Wordpress, Apache			
NGINX, AWS (EC2, RDS, S3), MySQL			
MongoDB, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap			
JavaScript, jQuery, Linux			
Windows, GIT (VCS)			

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Category: General

Job Type: Permanent

Physically Challenged: No

Employment Status: Full time